SM Mashuque

347-694-9301

sm.mashuq@gmail.com smmashuq.com

linkedin.com/in/smmashuq

PROFILE

I am always excited to build things with programming. I like learning new things about designing and building software. So far my experience has been more about working with backend technologies, but I do have interest in front-end technologies.

EDUCATION

Cornell University, B.S.

05/2020

- Cumulative GPA: 3.3
- Major in Information Science. Minor in Computer Science.
- Relevant courses taken include OO Programming in Python, Data Science in Python, Data Structures in Java, Backend Web Development in PHP, and Systems Organization and Programming in C/C++.

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant in INFO/CS 2300: Backend Web Design 08/2018 - 12/2018

Cornell University

- Helped students with questions relating to server side data processing and creating dynamic pages using HTML, PHP, and SQLite.
- Met with professor weekly and helped grade assignments.

Software Engineer Intern

06/2018 - 08/2018

SinglePlatform

- Django MVC: Updated existing models, views, templates, and wrote unit tests.
- Created an API endpoint with pagination for restaurant locations, menus, and photos data using Django REST framework.
- Created asynchronous tasks to update models, and send emails using Celery and SendGrid.
- Applied view restrictions with Python decorators.
- Created a GUI app in Python for internal use to automate schedule creation process using Google Calendar API

Python Tutor

08/2017 - 05/2018

Cornell University

 Met with CS 1110 course students weekly and provided assistance with Python questions relating to homework, assignments, and exams.

PROJECTS

Takk - A Fundraising Platform for Higher Education.

02/2019 - 05/2019

- Served as the lead developer. Designed and implemented an MVP with the Django Framework.
- Integrated Twilio and Stripe API with the Django application to enable phone calling and payment processing.
- Oversaw all aspects of the project and Managed iterative improvement of the MVP.

Emulated RISC-V CPU

03/2019 - 04/2019

- Created a five stage pipelined CPU in Logisim.
- Adheres to the RISC-V ISA specifications.

Live Nasdaq Data

10/2018 - 11/2018

- Built a small web app to show live stock data.
- Integrated the app with IEX API for displaying latest stock price information.
- Built a React frontend with Django REST backend.

SKILLS

React

jQuery

D3.js

Programming Languages

Python	
Java	
C	
C++	
JavaScript	
PHP	
Databases	
PostgreSQL	
SQLite	
Redis	
Frameworks	
Django	
Angular	
Libraries	
NumPy	